[

Browse Map

Explore away](https://naturalatlas.com/map)[

Explore Map Collection

Check out our basemaps](https://naturalatlas.com/maps)[

Print a Map Plus

Generate a high-quality PDF](https://naturalatlas.com/map/print)

[

Field Guide

Discover local flora, fauna, geology, and more](https://naturalatlas.com/signin)

[

Local Flora & Fauna

Learn the ecology of your area](https://naturalatlas.com/signin)[

Local Geology

Learn the geologic formation at your feet](https://naturalatlas.com/signin)

[Get Started](https://naturalatlas.com/signin) or [Sign In](https://naturalatlas.com/signin)

Privacy Policy
==============

It is the policy of Natural Atlas Inc. (“Natural Atlas”, “We”, “Us”) to respect your privacy regarding any information we may collect while operating our products, software, services, widgets, and websites (collectively, the “Services”)

_Last Update: May 24, 2018_

[](https://github.com/naturalatlas/legal/blob/master/privacy.md#information-we-collect)Information We Collect
-------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------

### [](https://github.com/naturalatlas/legal/blob/master/privacy.md#recordings--content-syncing)Recordings & Content Syncing

Recordings you make using the app are _public_ by default. When you record a trip, note, or photo using the app it automatically get synced to your public profile at naturalatlas.com where friends, family, or anyone interested can browse them. To record private notes, trips, and photos using the app you must upgrade your account and specify that the recording should be made private. (Notes classified as something sensitive like petroglyphs, ruins, caves, most fossils, etc are private by default to protect the resource)

### [](https://github.com/naturalatlas/legal/blob/master/privacy.md#usage-information)Usage Information

When you use Natural Atlas Services we collect basic information about how you use the Services. This includes collecting information about the Content you view and interact with and information about the device and/or browser you are using. Natural Atlas’ purpose in collecting this information is to better understand how Natural Atlas’ visitors use its services and improve and personalize their experiences. Some of this information may be personally-identifying.

Here are some examples of information we collect:

* Device operating system, type, device identifiers, and versions.
* IP address
* Your device’s geographic location
* Content you view or interact with

### [](https://github.com/naturalatlas/legal/blob/master/privacy.md#payment-information)Payment Information

If you make a payment on Natural Atlas (upgrading your account for example), we collect information about the purchase. This includes your payment information, shipping and billing information, and contact details. Credit Card data is stored securely with [Stripe](https://stripe.com/) (a widely-used PCI compliant payment processor), not with Natural Atlas. _Full credit card details are not transmitted to Natural Atlas._

### [](https://github.com/naturalatlas/legal/blob/master/privacy.md#cookies)Cookies

A cookie is a string of information that a website stores on a visitor’s computer, and that the visitor’s browser provides to the website each time the visitor returns. Natural Atlas uses cookies to help Natural Atlas identify and track visitors, their usage of Natural Atlas website, and their website access preferences. Natural Atlas visitors who do not wish to have cookies placed on their computers should set their browsers to refuse cookies before using Natural Atlas’s websites, with the drawback that certain features of Natural Atlas’s websites may not function properly without the aid of cookies.

### [](https://github.com/naturalatlas/legal/blob/master/privacy.md#log-files)Log Files

Information in our logs includes IP addresses, requested URLs, browser type, referring websites, date/time stamps, and device platform. The purpose of storing this information is to analyze trends (for product and infrastructure planning purposes), identify misuse, and protect the service.

### [](https://github.com/naturalatlas/legal/blob/master/privacy.md#map-views)Map Views

When viewing Natural Atlas maps on Natural Atlas and on third-party websites and services, we log requested map tiles to determine viewing metrics and for billing purposes (in some cases).

[](https://github.com/naturalatlas/legal/blob/master/privacy.md#when-we-disclose-information)When We Disclose Information
-------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------

### [](https://github.com/naturalatlas/legal/blob/master/privacy.md#aggregated-statistics)Aggregated Statistics

Natural Atlas may collect statistics about the behavior of visitors to its services. Natural Atlas may display this information publicly or provide it to others. However, Natural Atlas does not disclose personally-identifying information other than as described below.

### [](https://github.com/naturalatlas/legal/blob/master/privacy.md#personally-identifying-information)Personally-Identifying Information

Natural Atlas discloses potentially personally-identifying and personally-identifying information only to those of its employees, contractors and affiliated organizations that (i) need to know that information in order to process it on Natural Atlas’s behalf or to provide services available on Natural Atlas’s websites and services, and (ii) that have agreed not to disclose it to others. Some of those employees, contractors and affiliated organizations may be located outside of your home country; by using Natural Atlas’s services, you consent to the transfer of such information to them. Natural Atlas will not rent or sell potentially personally-identifying and personally-identifying information to anyone. Other than to its employees, contractors and affiliated organizations, as described above, Natural Atlas discloses potentially personally-identifying and personally-identifying information only in response to a subpoena, court order or other governmental request, or when Natural Atlas believes in good faith that disclosure is reasonably necessary to protect the property or rights of Natural Atlas, third parties or the public at large. If you are a registered user of a Natural Atlas service and have supplied your email address, Natural Atlas may occasionally send you an email to tell you about new features, solicit your feedback, or just keep you up to date with what’s going on with Natural Atlas and our products. We primarily use our blog to communicate this type of information, so we expect to keep this type of email to a minimum. If you send us a request (for example via a support email or via one of our feedback mechanisms), we reserve the right to publish it in order to help us clarify or respond to your request or to help us support other users. Natural Atlas takes all measures reasonably necessary to protect against the unauthorized access, use, alteration or destruction of potentially personally-identifying and personally-identifying information.

### [](https://github.com/naturalatlas/legal/blob/master/privacy.md#business-transfers)Business Transfers

If Natural Atlas, or substantially all of its assets, were acquired, or in the unlikely event that Natural Atlas goes out of business or enters bankruptcy, user information would be one of the assets that is transferred or acquired by a third party. You acknowledge that such transfers may occur, and that any acquirer of Natural Atlas may continue to use your personal information as set forth in this policy.

### [](https://github.com/naturalatlas/legal/blob/master/privacy.md#ads)Ads

Ads appearing on any of our services may be delivered to users by advertising partners, who may set cookies. These cookies allow the ad server to recognize your computer each time they send you an online advertisement to compile information about you or others who use your computer. This information allows ad networks to, among other things, deliver targeted advertisements that they believe will be of most interest to you. This Privacy Policy covers the use of cookies by Natural Atlas and does not cover the use of cookies by any advertisers.

[](https://github.com/naturalatlas/legal/blob/master/privacy.md#how-we-protect-your-information)How We Protect Your Information
-------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------

Natural Atlas follows industry-standard security practices to keep your data safe. This includes:

* Industry-standard SSL (HTTPS) to protect information in flight to and from your devices and our servers. This secures the content of the information being transmitted and protects against tampering by intermediate third parties.
* Our servers are protected against intrusion via firewalls, strict access control policies, and other technical measures.
* Personnel given direct access to our servers is limited to Natural Atlas employees and contractors that are contractually bound to keep information confidential.

### [](https://github.com/naturalatlas/legal/blob/master/privacy.md#disclaimer)Disclaimer

While Natural Atlas continuously works to protect your personal information, it should be noted that no service is 100% secure and Natural Atlas cannot ensure or warrant the security of any information you transmit to us.

[](https://github.com/naturalatlas/legal/blob/master/privacy.md#your-choices-regarding-your-data)Your Choices Regarding Your Data
---------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------

* **Modify / Delete Own Content** – At any time you can modify, correct, or remove your submitted content to Natural Atlas.
* **Opt-Out of Email Communications** – You can unsubscribe from marketing communications by clicking the “Unsubscribe” link at the bottom of marketing emails.
* **Withdraw Consent to iOS Permissions** – If using the Natural Atlas iOS app, you can always disallow Natural Atlas access to location information and opt-out of notifications by adjusting the App Permissions using the operating system’s Settings app.
* **Right to Data Export** – If you would like a copy of all of your user data including recorded notes, trips, photos, etc, contact [hello@naturalatlas.com](mailto:hello@naturalatlas.com) and we will aggregate it and provide it to you.

[](https://github.com/naturalatlas/legal/blob/master/privacy.md#retention-of-information)Retention of Information
-----------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------

Any personal content you submit that’s tied to your profile on Natural Atlas is retained permanently unless you delete it or delete your account. You may delete your account at any time, for any reason at [https://naturalatlas.com/account](https://naturalatlas.com/account).

Upon deletion, Natural Atlas will attempt to immediately make the deleted content unavailable. Be aware that certain information may live in caches temporarily for a few days. Content indexed by searches engines such as Google may take considerably longer to disappear.

### [](https://github.com/naturalatlas/legal/blob/master/privacy.md#data-removal-caveats)Data Removal Caveats

* Content submitted to public wiki pages (e.g. place pages) will not be deleted if you delete your account on Natural Atlas. You do reserve the right to remove any content that you once added to these pages – but this must be done by yourself manually prior to account deletion, as there is no good technical way to achieve this automatically.
* Publicly recorded trips, field notes, and other submitted public content may be retained in an anonymized form after deletion to aid with map and product improvements and for aggregate statistics.
* Other aggregated, de-personalized, anonymized information may be retained indefinitely.

[](https://github.com/naturalatlas/legal/blob/master/privacy.md#contact)Contact
-------------------------------------------------------------------------------

_If you have questions, comments, or complaints about these policies or need help in managing your content, please contact [hello@naturalatlas.com](mailto:hello@naturalatlas.com)._

For the sake of European GDPR compliance, the contact information for Natural Atlas’s appointed Data Protection Officer (DPO) is:

    Brian Reavis
    Natural Atlas, Inc.
    1108 14th St. #196
    Cody, WY 82414
    brian@naturalatlas.com

[](https://github.com/naturalatlas/legal/blob/master/privacy.md#privacy-policy-changes)Privacy Policy Changes
-------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------

Although most changes are likely to be minor, Natural Atlas may change its Privacy Policy from time to time, and in Natural Atlas’s sole discretion. Natural Atlas encourages visitors to frequently check this page for any changes to its Privacy Policy.

When we make changes, we’ll update the “Last Update” date at the top of the Privacy Policy and post it on our site(s). If we make material changes to it or the ways we process personal information, we will notify you. For example, this may entail a prominent notice on our site(s) and services and/or directly sending you a notification by email or other means.

Your continued use of this site after any change in this Privacy Policy will constitute your acceptance of such change.

Nature's Best Map & Field Recorder In Your Pocket

Track your next hike and the memories and discoveries along the way.

Explore

Apps

[

iOS](https://apps.apple.com/us/app/natural-atlas/id1144214110?platform=iphone)[

Android](https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.naturalatlas.NaturalAtlas)

Upgrade

[Natural Atlas

](https://naturalatlas.com/upgrade)[Gift Natural Atlas

](https://naturalatlas.com/gift)

Help

Company

Follow Us

[

Twitter](https://twitter.com/naturalatlas)[

Instagram](https://instagram.com/natural.atlas)[

Facebook](https://www.facebook.com/naturalatlas)

Copyright © 2024 Natural Atlas, Inc.Born in Wyoming and the Greater Yellowstone Ecosystem
